XUN CHEN

330 Crescent Village Cir. San Jose, CA xunchen369@gmail.com +1(973)-767-9194

ABOUT ME

Creative Front-End Engineer with strong engineering background, specialized in Front-End architecture, Data Visualization, and User Interface Design. I like to inspire myself by learning new technologies, perfecting techniques through constant practice and applying them for innovation.

SKILLS

Image/Vector Graphics Editing Wireframing UI Design Data Visualization Web Development Front-End Testing Command Line VIM Editor

TECHNOLOGIES

ES5,ES6,ES7 **SCSS** Node.js ReactJS Redux/Redux-Thunk/Redux-Saga D3.js Three.js Webpack/Gulp/Grunt Git Sketch/Illustrator/Photoshop

LANGUAGE

English Chinese

EXPERIENCE

TARGET, SUNNYVALE, CA

Apr 2016 - May 2018

Lead Data Engineer

- Designed and implemented UI/UX wireframes and mock ups using Sketch, Photoshop and
- Developed Several Data Visualization Web based Dashboards using D3.js, Angular 1.X and
- Spearheaded the architecture, design, feature of a generalized log streaming platform web
- Mentored other front-end engineers and consulted for other teams at Target.
- Implemented and contributed to tools that aided Front-End Development at Target.

AKUDA LABS, SAN JOSE, CA

Jul 2015 - Apr 2016

Software Engineer

- Developed a query based full-stack web application that allows cross cluster queries of Elastic Search indices.
- Programmed a Tableau Web Data Connector to connect Tableau with our internal API calls.
- Built a web application that visualizes geo location data, sentiment data, and traffic from social media on the topics of the 2016 election using Node.js, AngularJS, and D3.js.

DELPHI, SHANGHAI, CHINA

Jun 2014 - Aug 2014

R&D Software Intern

- Implemented a web application that allows users to tune into various radio channels from www.qingting.fm for Delphi's automobile infotainment system using Sencha Touch.
- Used RESTFUL API to retrieve live radio streaming data from Qingting's internal API using a PHP backend.

VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE

SHANGHAI WORLD EXPO 2010, SHANGHAI, **CHINA**

Jun 2010 - Jul 2010

Chinese/English Translator

• Volunteered at a service stand as a translator and guide for visitors of the Shanghai World EXPO 2010.

EDUCATION

University of Illinois at Urbana Champaign

Aug 2011 - May 2015

Bachelor of Science in Computer Engineering

INTERESTS & ACTIVITIES

Piano Table Tennis Traveling Stock Trading Desktop Widget Development PC Customization